<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="app_name">02_proyecto</string>

    <string-array name="ArrayHechos">
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_0">Chemical symbol: Zinc has the chemical symbol on the periodic table.
            It is element number 30 on the table.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_1">Discovery: Zinc has been known and used since ancient times,
            but it was first isolated as an element in its metallic form in the 13th century in India.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_2">Color and Luster: Zinc is a bluish-white metal with a metallic luster when freshly exposed to the atmosphere.
            However, it can become dull over time due to the formation of an oxide layer on its surface.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_3">Abundance: Zinc is the 24th most abundant element in the Earth</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_4">Industrial Uses: Zinc is used in numerous industrial applications, including the galvanization of steel to protect it from corrosion,
            the production of metal alloys (such as brass and bronze), and in battery production.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_5"> Biological Importance: Zinc is an essential micronutrient for living organisms, including humans.
            It is necessary for a variety of biological functions, including the functioning of enzymes and the regulation of the immune system.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_6">Recycling: Zinc is highly recyclable. Zinc recycling is economically viable and environmentally beneficial,
            as it reduces the need to extract and process more zinc ore.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_7">Electric Conductivity: Zinc is a good conductor of electricity and is used in electrical applications such as the production of batteries and cells..</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_8">Effect of Zinc Fumes: Inhaling zinc fumes can cause symptoms similar to the flu, known as metal fume fever.
            It is a temporary condition that typically occurs when zinc is heated.</item>
        <item name ="Hecho_curioso_9">
            Toxicity: While zinc is essential for life, excessive intake of zinc through diet or occupational exposure to high concentrations of zinc can be toxic and cause health problems,
            such as nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>


